Liam Giles

liamthomasgiles1702@gmail.com

07857317891

Personal Statement

I am an energetic, motivated and driven person with a wide range of work and life experience. Studying a Bachelor's degree in Theoretical Physics, I have been able to develop excellent time management, team-working, and problem-solving skills. My BSc final year project and dissertation focused on the development of a bespoke Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) for the classification of image-like output data for a new type of opaque liquid particle detector, which was able to achieve unprecedented classification accuracy between electrons and gamma photons. This allowed me to land an internship at MeVitae, where I gained experience working on production-ready neural networks, web scraper algorithms and managing a back-end database for an internal automated lead generation tool for B2B sales.

Prior to and during my studies, I worked in a number of psychiatric hospitals with Cygnet Healthcare. During this time I learned invaluable interpersonal skills, interacting with and caring for individuals with a range of conditions, providing encouragement and practical assistance in their day-to-day lives.

Skills

- Highly proficient with Python (including Tensorflow, PyTorch, NumPy) and HTML, CSS, and JavaScript (including Canvas API, React, Next.js). Experience writing C# for production-level code during my internship, and some familiarity with PHP, Go, Java and C.
- Deep knowledge of machine learning principles, with an emphasis on CNNs for image classification, fine-tuning and prompt engineering Large Language Models (LLMs), and word embeddings for text classification.
- Rich work experience has given me the communication skills to work professionally in any environment.
- Highest grades in university came from Thermal & Statistical Physics (>90%) and Condensed State Physics (\sim 80%).
- Proficient with Git and GitHub which have been used to keep track of all personal and work projects. See my public repositories at https://www.github.com/liamtgiles17.
- Experience in constructing technical reports with LATEX, and PowerPoint presentations documenting my work.
- Not afraid of working hard or going above and beyond for work I believe in, as evidenced by my current line of work and choice of degree course.

Employment

• MeVitae - Project Delivery Assistant (Intern)

July 2024 and August - September 2024

Outline: Worked closely with a supervisor to develop an internal automated sales tool, utilising web scraper algorithms, some API calls, and multiple statistical models/neural networks.

• Cygnet Healthcare - Mental Health Support Worker

February 2019 - September 2020 and August 2023 - Present

Outline: Delivering person-centered care to individuals with compassion and empathy, providing physical and emotional support and helping people re-gain control of their lives.

• Just Eat - Delivery Driver

September 2021 - May 2023

Outline: Ensuring food is delivered in a timely and efficient manner.

Education

- Graduated in BSc Theoretical Physics at the University of Sussex, achieving a final grade of 2(ii) (July 2024).
- 3 A-Levels at King Edward VI College, Stourbridge (2016-2018):
 - Mathematics: A
 - Physics: C
 - Further Mathematics: D
- 12 GCSEs at Dormston School, Dudley (2A*, 8A, 2B) (2011-2016).

Hobbies / Interests

- Study and play chess competitively with Mercia Chess Club.
- Train Brazilian Jiu-Jitsu.
- Recreational programming, in particular game and web development and implementing neural networks from scratch.